ustravel.org 2019-10-24

# Privacy Policy | U.S. Travel Association

**Privacy Policy - Last Updated: April 24, 2019**

This statement outlines the policies and practices of U.S. Travel Association (“U.S. Travel”, “We” or “Us”) regarding the collection and use of Your personal information from Your visit at [ustravel.org](http://www.ustravel.org/) or any other websites owned or operated by U.S. Travel, such as ipw.com, travelcoalition.org, esto.ustravel.org, dailygetaways.com; and projecttimeoff.com (collectively, the “Site” or “Sites”), on Our social media pages, in email, text, and other electronic messages between you and the Sites. It includes our policies for U.S. Travel Members and non-members.

The websites or apps of third parties to which we provide information to or which provide information to Us may have their own privacy policies, which We encourage you to read before providing information on or through them.

All terms used herein are defined in our Terms of Use. By using the Sites or the services provided through this Sites (the “Services”), You acknowledge that We may collect information about you, and use and disclose such information as described in this Privacy Policy. Your use of the Sites or Services indicates your acceptance of the terms of this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into the U.S. Travel Terms of Use.

THE SITES AND SERVICES ARE HOSTED IN THE UNITED STATES. IF YOU ARE A USER ACCESSING THE SITES OR SERVICES FROM THE EUROPEAN UNION, ASIA, OR ANY OTHER REGION WITH LAWS OR REGULATIONS GOVERNING PERSONAL DATA COLLECTION, USE, AND DISCLOSURE THAT DIFFER FROM UNITED STATES LAWS, PLEASE BE ADVISED THAT THROUGH YOUR CONTINUED USE OF THE SITES OR SERVICES, WHICH IS GOVERNED BY UNITED STATES LAW, THIS PRIVACY POLICY, AND OUR TERMS OF SERVICE, YOU ARE TRANSFERRING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION TO THE UNITED STATES, AND YOU CONSENT TO THAT TRANSFER. ADDITIONALLY, YOU UNDERSTAND THAT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE PROCESSED IN COUNTRIES (INCLUDING THE UNITED STATES) WHERE LAWS REGARDING PROCESSING PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE DIFFERENT OR LESS STRINGENT THAN IN YOUR HOME JURISDICTION.

Please read this policy carefully to understand Our policies and practices regarding Your information and how We will treat it. If you do not agree with Our policies and practices, Your choice is not to use Our Sites or the Services. By accessing or using the Sites, You agree to this Privacy Policy. This Policy may change from time to time ( _see_ Changes to U.S. Travel’s Privacy Policy, below). Your continued use of the Sites after We make changes or your affirmative acceptance of such changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes, so please check the Policy periodically for updates.

**Information We Collect, How We Use It and How You Can Update/Delete ItAccessing and Modifying Your Personal Information.**

**You control the personally identifiable information about you, such as your name, address, phone number and email address (“Personal Information”), that you share with us. You can correct, delete, or modify this data at any time. You can also delete your account. We also provide you tools to restrict or withdraw consent where applicable for the use of data you have provided to U.S. Travel Association. And we provide easy ways for you to contact us.**

If you are a registered user of our Services, we provide you with tools and account settings to access, correct, delete, or modify the Personal Information you provided to us and associated with your account. If you have granted us consent to access and use your personal data, you can withdraw that consent at any time. You can request that we stop using your personal data for certain or all purposes, or for a certain amount of time, or that we stop sharing your personal data with third parties.

You can also permanently delete your account. If you follow the instructions here, your account will be deleted within ten (10) business days. If you wish to reinstate your account, you must contact U.S. Travel Association directly at the contact information below.  Keep in mind that third parties to whom U.S. Travel Association has transmitted your data with your consent may still retain copies of your Personal Information even after you have deleted the information from, or deleted, your account with U.S. Travel Association. If you would like a copy of the Personal Information we have collected about you, or if you need a list of entities to whom your personal data has been transmitted, please contact U.S. Travel Association directly at the contact information below.

**Browsing**

When You browse our Sites, We do not collect Personal Information, unless You voluntarily provide it to us. This means that We will not know your Personal Information just because You browse our Sites unless You have created an account and login when You access the Sites or access the Sites from a link in an email that We sent to you.

When We need to collect Personal Information from You to provide You with a particular service, We will ask You to voluntarily supply Us with the information We need, as explained below.

**General Information Collected**

To monitor site usage and improve the quality of our Sites, We gather general information about the use of our Sites. We use web server logs and industry-standard website statistics software to count the number of users who visit our Sites and to count the number of views of particular pages, as well as to track other general statistics about our Sites. We do not track individual users' visits to our Sites. At times U.S. Travel may share with third parties aggregate, anonymous information about overall usage of our Sites and other Internet services that We collect, to provide general information about our Internet services, sell advertising, or establish sponsorships or other business relationships.

**Information Collected from Surveys**

We may conduct online surveys via pop-up windows on our Sites. Participation in such surveys is voluntary and You may decline to participate. In general, the data collected in such surveys will be used by U.S. Travel and not shared with any third parties.

**Information Collected to Process a Transaction**

To conduct a transaction on a U.S. Travel Sites, visitors must have, or create, a login account. Visitors who are Members of U.S. Travel will use their member login ( _i.e_., user name) and password. More information on Members is detailed below. Non-members visitors will need to create an account to generate a unique login and password. Information collected from non-members may include your name, address, telephone and fax numbers, email address, and credit card number or other payment information. More information about account information can be found in the Terms of Use.

**Information Payment Method**

Payment information, such as your credit card details, is collected only to process a transaction and is stored in an encrypted format. We use reasonable measures to ensure your payment information is not vulnerable to theft or interception. We will not store or distribute your payment information in a manner that is not necessary for processing a transaction.

**Members' Information**

U.S. Travel offers members certain services through the restricted-access “Members Only” section of our Sites. In the Members Only section, members can access and update their Member Profiles, which include Personal Information We have collected from each member as part of their membership application. Member Profiles are maintained for the Main and Associate member contacts in our main membership database. This information includes information such as member ID number, name, firm/organization, address, telephone and fax numbers, and email address.

The Member Profiles are used by U.S. Travel to distribute certain marketing materials by mail, fax or email. If You are a member and wish to elect not to be included in any of these communications, You may opt-out using the methods listed below.

**Information Collected to Access Certain Private Sections**

U.S. Travel collects a password for each member who uses the online Members Section of the Sites, or the event attendees section of certain of our Sites. This information is used to verify Your identity in order to prevent unauthorized access to these section and Your Personal Information. Only a small number of U.S. Travel employees and employees at our third-party software vendors have access to this information. It is accessed only when necessary to provide members with online account-related information, provide technical support, or diagnose or repair problems with the Members Only or Attendees sections. You may update your Personal Information if You have registered at the Sites by emailing Us at [feedback@ustravel.org](mailto:feedback@ustravel.org) from your email address on record or, if You have access to the Members Only section of the Sites, by editing your profile within that section. We may not be able to update any information previously disclosed to a third party. Your Personal Information is necessary in order for Us to send You newsletters or other communications or to provide You access to the Members Only section of the Sites. Therefore, if You delete such necessary information We may not be able to provide You certain Services.

The safety and security of Your information also depends on You. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password for access to certain parts of our Sites, You are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask You not to share Your password with anyone.

**Emails/Newsletters**

It is our intention to only send You email communications that You want to receive. When You provide Us with your email address by creating a login account, We will periodically contact You via email about U.S. Travel programs and services. Every time You receive an email, You will be provided the choice to opt-out of future emails by following the instructions provided in the email. You may also opt-out by emailing [ **feedback@ustravel.org**](mailto:feedback@ustravel.org) or sending a letter to:

U.S. Travel Association  
1100 New York Avenue, NW, Suite 450  
Washington, DC 20005  
United States of America

Please allow 10 business days for Us to process your opt-out and include your email address if You opt-out via postal mail. Note that even if You unsubscribe or opt-out, We may still send You transactional, relationship or service-related emails.

Please note that U.S. Travel will never send You an email requesting your password, credit card number, social security number or other similar personal or private identification information. If You receive an email that looks like it is from U.S. Travel, but asks You for personal information, it is a fraudulent email and You should not reply or provide such information.

**Submitting Information and Materials**

Please be aware that whenever You voluntarily post information or materials to public areas on the Sites or any other public forums, such information and materials can be accessed by the public. If You submit information, comments or materials to the Sites or on Our social media pages or apps, You agree that we may freely use them, along with your name and location, as set forth in our Terms of Use.

**Retention of Information and Materials**

We retain the Personal Information and materials We may collect and you provide Us for no longer than is reasonably necessary for us to achieve the purposes for which you have provided it to Us, or to the extent reasonably necessary for Us to protect our rights, or as may be required to fulfill Our legal obligations.

**Disclosure of Information to Third Parties**

U.S. Travel uses the services of third parties, such as interactive marketing agencies, market researchers and email service providers, to assist Us with marketing and promoting our Sites. These parties are contractually prohibited from using personally identifiable information for any purpose other than for the purpose U.S. Travel specifies. We do provide non-personally identifiable information to certain service providers for their use on an aggregated basis for the purpose of performing their contractual obligations to us. We do not permit the sale of Personal Information, with a limited exception for Member-related and IPW transactions.We also may disclose Personal Information in certain situations.

You hereby consent to our sharing of Personal Information for the following purposes:

  * To third party vendors who help Us make the Sites or Services available or who support our business;
  * To third parties to whom You ask Us to send Personal Information (for example, see below regarding “Event Registrations”);
  * To third party sponsors and partners who may use the Personal Information for marketing purposes ( _see_ “Event Registrations,” below);
  * To fulfill the purpose for which you provide it;
  * For any other purpose disclosed by Us when you provide the information;
  * If We believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to: (a) resolve disputes, investigate problems, or enforce our Terms of Use; (b) comply with applicable laws or respond to requests from law enforcement or other government officials; or (c) protect or defend the rights or property of U.S. Travel, you, or third parties; . This includes, without limitation, exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection;
  * To a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of U.S. Travel’s assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which Personal Information held by U.S. Travel about our Site users is among the assets transferred;
  * To enforce or apply Our Terms of Use or terms of sale of goods or services, and other agreements, including for billing and collection purposes.

**Grounds for Use of Personal Information**

We rely on the following legal bases for processing and use of your Personal Information:

  * **Performance of a Contract:** We may collect and use your Personal Information that is necessary for Us to enter into a contract with you or to fulfill a contract that you may have entered with us, or to take steps requested by you prior to entering into a contract with Us, for example, when you decide to register with Us to attend certain U.S. Travel events, such as IPW, ESTO, among other of Our conferences and events. `

  * **Legitimate Interests:** We may use your Personal Information as necessary for our letitimate interests consistent with the products, services, and content on [ustravel.org](http://www.ustravel.org/) or any other websites owned or operated by U.S. Travel, such as ipw.com, travelcoalition.org, esto.ustravel.org, dailygetaways.com; and projectttimeoff.com, on Our social media pages, in email, text, and other electronic messages between you and the foregoing sites, and for Our Promotions.

  * **Consent:** We also may collect and share your information with your consent. To withdraw your consent, [you may contact Us via Our contact information](https://www.ustravel.org/contact-us), which is provided to you below.

Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy, You will be notified when your Personal Information may be shared with third parties, and will be given the option to prevent the sharing of this information.

**Event Registrations**

By registering for or attending certain events, such as IPW, ESTO and other conferences, U.S. Travel may use your Personal Information to: (a) enable your event registration; (b) market U.S. Travel opportunities in which you may be interested; (c) share your Personal Information with third parties that perform services on behalf of U.S. Travel in connection with the event, including, but not limited to, database management, event housing and transportation; and (d) share your Personal Information with third parties who sponsor the event for their marketing purposes. To opt out of receiving email communications from any such companies, you may unsubscribe from their email marketing lists using the information provided in such email communications. To opt-out of U.S. Travel communications, please follow the methods detailed below.

**Cookies and Pixel Tags**

Our Sites use “Cookie” technology. “Cookies” are encrypted strings of text that a website stores on a user's computer. Our Sites require the use of a “Session” Cookie when accessing the online traveler community. “Session” Cookies are temporary and are automatically deleted once You close your internet browser. Session Cookies allow You to log-in and then view and update your content throughout the Sites during the same session or visit. Our Sites use a “Persistent” Cookie to direct You to the correct country/language version of our Sites for subsequent visits. Persistent Cookies remain on your computer until You delete them or are otherwise removed upon expiration. We do not use Cookies to ascertain any personally identifiable information about You apart from what You voluntarily provide us. Cookies do not corrupt or damage your computer, programs, or computer files. Most browsers have an option to reject or disable cookies, which will prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, as well as (depending on the sophistication of your browser software) allowing You to decide on acceptance of each new cookie in a variety of ways. Although You can block cookies and similar technology, your experience of the Sites and Services could be affected by doing so.

Pixel tags are not visible to the user of the Sites and consist of a few lines of computer code. Pixel tags are not used to collect any personally identifiable information about you. Our Sites use pixel tags to track the aggregate number of page views made on our Sites by all Sites visitors. We also use social media pixels in compliance with the policies of the various social media sites, such as Facebook, Twitter and LinkedIn, to track cookies. These pixels allow social media sites to track visitors to outside websites in order to tailor the advertising messages that users see while visiting that social media website. Our email service provider uses pixel tags to determine your ability to receive HTML-based email messages. This capability helps our service provider send email in a format You can read. The sensor does not collect or use any other information. Pixel tags also allow Us to know how many users open an email and allow our service provider to compile aggregated statistics about an email campaign for us.

**Promotions**

We have strategic marketing relationships with select third party organizations (e.g., American Express) to offer certain travel related products and services at discounted prices. As part of the purchase process for these products and services You will be required to provide Personal Information such as your name, address, email address, telephone number and credit card information. This information will be used by Us and will be provided to the associated third party organizations (e.g., hotel, credit card processor) to execute the transaction. As part of these promotions You will also be given a choice to opt-in into periodic emails from U.S. Travel and the organizations We have selected to offer promotions so that We can keep You informed of future offers and promotions that may be of interest. Please note that there are specific terms and conditions that will be unique to each promotion. An example is the requirement to be a member of the loyalty program for a hotel brand that is included in the promotion. You should carefully review the terms and conditions associated with each promotion before making a purchase.

**Securing Your Information**

The Personal Information You provide is encrypted and sent to Us using a secure method. We treat personal information You provide as confidential information, and We use commercially reasonable security measures to protect personal information from unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction. After Personal Information reaches U.S. Travel, it is stored on a secure server that resides behind firewalls designed to block unauthorized access.

However, please understand that no one can provide an absolute guarantee that information intended to be maintained as private, whether transmitted via the Internet or otherwise, cannot be accessed inappropriately or unlawfully by third parties. We have taken and will continue to take reasonable steps to ensure the secure and safe transmission of your personal information. You understand and agree that such steps do not guarantee that use of the Sites is invulnerable to all security breaches, and that U.S. Travel makes no warranty, guarantee, or representation that use of any portion of our Sites is protected from viruses, security threats or other vulnerabilities.

In the event of a security breach, U.S. Travel will promptly notify you of any unauthorized access to your Personal Information. U.S. Travel has incident management policies and procedures in place to handle such an event.

**Other Sites**

U.S. Travel is only responsible for the Privacy Policy and content of its Sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the use of cookies on websites from which You have accessed this Sites, or non-U.S. Travel websites that You may access from this Sites. U.S. Travel encourages You to review the policies of other websites that You may access from the Sites. 

**Legal Issues**

This is a United States website and is subject to laws of the United States and the District of Columbia. U.S. Travel may disclose personally identifiable information without your permission if required by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) comply with legal requirements or legal process served on U.S. Travel or one of its affiliates, or (b) investigate or protect against harmful activities to U.S. Travel or its associates, property (including our Sites) or to others.

**Personal Information of** **Children Under Age 16**

The Sites are not intended for children under 16 years of age. No one under age 16 may provide any Personal Information to or on the Sites. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under 16. If you are under 16, do not use or provide any information on the Sites or on or through any of its features/register on the Sites, make any purchases through the Sites, use any of the interactive or public comment features of the Sites or provide any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, email address, or any screen name or user name you may use. If We learn we have collected or received Personal Information from a child under 16 without verification of parental consent, We will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 16, please contact us at the email or mailing address below.

**Changes to U.S. Travel’s Privacy Policy**

In the future, We may need to change this Privacy Policy. All changes will be made here so that You will always know what information We gather, how We might use that information and whether We will disclose it to anyone. This policy was last updated effective April 25, 2019.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as the “Shine The Light” law, permits our users who are residents of the State of California in the United States to annually request and obtain, at no charge, information about the personal information (if any) We have disclosed to third parties for direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. This information would include a list of the categories of personal information that was shared and the names and addresses of all third parties with which We shared information in the immediately preceding calendar year. If You are a California resident and would like to make such a request, please submit your request to the email or mailing address below.

**Contacting U.S. Travel About Privacy Issues**

If You have any comments, suggestions or questions about privacy policy, please contact us:

By email at: [feedback@ustravel.org](mailto:feedback@ustravel.org)  
By phone at: 202.408.8422  
By fax at: 202.408.1255

By mail at:  
 **Privacy Issues**  
U.S. Travel Association  
1100 New York Avenue, NW, Suite 450 W  
Washington, DC 20005
